Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Covid-19 Archive AD.RG.030.2
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
NYU Abu Dhabi Covid Archive
2020-2022
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG.030.2
252 Megabytes of digital records
1 Linear Feet in one document box
The NYU Abu Dhabi Covid-19 Archive includes records, artifacts, and stories that help document how the pandemic was experienced on this campus and by members of the community.
Biographical / Historical
The Covid-19 Archive is a collecting project of the NYUAD Library's Archives and Special Collections. It was an initiative that was launched in April 2020 on the heels of the announcement of a global pandemic; of a campus-wide pivot to remote teaching, learning, and non-essential operations; and a city-wide "lockdown" in Abu Dhabi and many cities around the world. The Covid-19 archival initiative began as a request from NYU Abu Dhabi Vice Chancellor Mariët Westermann to ensure the University was "archiving this moment." In a meeting called and led by Westermann herself, the Library and its Archives and Special Collections team were asked to help ensure that the record of the University's decisions, and its community members' experiences, would be preserved in real time.
While acknowledging that a record of how the University responded to and experienced the Covid-19 pandemic would largely emerge from the routine preservation of administrative, operational, academic planning, and other institutional records, the team began planning more targeted approaches to documentation through outreach to Communications and Facilities departments, development of a community archive donation opportunity, and a leadership oral history project.
From spring 2020 through early 2021, similar efforts around the world were happening in tandem, including a "Covid-19 Oral History Project" led by media producers at NYU in New York (for which Westermann and some leaders at NYU Abu Dhabi were invited to participate).
The Covid-19 Archive represents collecting efforts that began in April 2020 and has continued through 2022.
Scope and Contents
The NYU Abu Dhabi Covid-19 Archive includes records, artifacts, creative works, and other memorabilia donated by campus departments and individuals; from images of campus "distancing" signage, to remnants of a campus in "lockdown."
Series that are open for research and browsing include materials solicited and acquired by the archivists from various departments, as well as materials contributed directly by community members.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Digital materials in the Covid-19 Archive have been acquired by a variety of means: via direct submission to the Covid-19 website submission page, through solicitation by the Archivist, and via routine records transfers from NYUAD departments. Physical materials have been acquired through either individual donations or through donations to the "Covid-19 Donations Bin," a collecting bin that was available to the community from May 2021 through September 2022.
Conditions Governing Access
Physical materials may be accessed in the Archives and Special Collections Reading Room, following walk-in hours or by appointment.
For remote access to digital materials, follow the "External Links" provided in this finding aid, which link directly to the University Archives online digital archives. This repository is available through authenticated access. For more information or questions about access, contact nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu to reach the department.
- A Campus in Lockdown, Spring 2020
  Scope and Contents
  A video slideshow compiled from images curated from four student photo essays, for Sohail Karmani's Spring 2020 course "Ethics of the Image." Created by Sohail Karmani on May 2, 2020. Images depict NYUAD campus during the early months of the COVID-19 pandemic and subsequent lockdown. The video was posted on several social media platforms and received many positive reviews. Photographs in the slide show were contributed by four of Sohail's students: Ghita Benhayoune, Killian Marie Dumont, Markus Abeler, and Michal Andrzejewski
- Campus Facilities Covid Signage (with examples), 2021
  - Covid Signage, May 2020
    Graphic materials prepared by the office of External Relations and Communications related to messaging for the campus community pertaining to Coronavirus and Covid.
    - Social-distancing-t-shirt-BACK, March, 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - Social-distancing-t-shirt-FRONT, March 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - Social-distancing-t-shirt-MOCK-UP, March 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - NYUAD-Physical-Distancing-Decals, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - PDA-Masks, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - Physical-Distancing, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - PDA-Stay-Home, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - PDA-Wash-Hands, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - icon-PDA-Masks, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - icon-PDA-Stay-Home, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - icon-PDA-Wash-Hands, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - icon-Physical-Distancing, April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - PDA-buying-masks, May 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - NYUAD-Community-Relief-Fund-WEB, May 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - Physical-Distancing-Elevator-Decal-3ft, May 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - Physical-Distancing-Floor-Decal-1ft, May 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
    - Physical-Distancing-Table-Decal-10x8, May 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Covid Signage)
  - Photos of Covid Signage, May 2020
    - Physical-distancing-decals-01 [ground decal], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-02 [bench decal], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-03 [tabletop decal], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-04 [tabletop decal], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-05 [tabletop decal close up], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-06 [elevator floor decal], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-07 [elevator floor decal], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-08 [elevator floor decal close up with person standing], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
    - Physical-distancing-decals-09 [ground decal], April 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_Photos of Covid Signage)
- NYUAD Dining Staff_ADNH, September 2020
  - Facebook Post, NYUAD Dining, September 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_NYUAD Dining_ADNH)
  - ADNH Thank You Board_COVID-19, September 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_NYUAD Dining_ADNH)
  - ADNH Thank you signs_COVID-19-2: Glenda, September 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_NYUAD Dining_ADNH)
  - ADNH Thank you signs_COVID-19-3: Santosh, September 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_NYUAD Dining_ADNH)
  - ADNH Thank you signs_COVID-19-4: Deepak, September 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_NYUAD Dining_ADNH)
  - ADNH Thank you signs_COVID-19-5: Rose, September 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_NYUAD Dining_ADNH)
- NYUAD Community Participatory Covid Archive, 2021-2022; 252 Megabytes comprised of 71 items.
  Materials in this series have been submitted either directly into the Covid Archive donations bin, or via the Covid Archive submission webpage online. Artwork, poetry, artifacts, research data, publications, announcements, and shared correspondence are just some of the types of material donated. This is a modest collection that provides a snapshot of community members experiences and expressions during the pandemic.
  - Physical Item Submissions
    - Kamil, Hamza. Empty bottle, hydroalcoholic solution, March-August 2020; Submission 18; The submitted item is an empty bottle that, according to the submitter, previously contained hydroalcoholic solution. Researchers must use gloves provided by Archives and Special Collections before accessing the item, and with the supervision of Archives and Special Collections staff. Submitter's handwritten description of the item has been retained with the item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      My submission is a hydroalcoholic solution given by the Hassan II University in Casablanca (Morocco) to its visitors and employees at the beginning of the pandemic in Morocco (March-August 2020).
    - Kamil, Hamza. Three Items, January, May, August 2021; Submission 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Three items:
      1- Ticket given while I was waiting to remove my tracker watch at the SEHA centre in Mina Zayed the 20 August 2021.
      2- Five "Encouragement" cards given by the campus dining/restaurant to help me endure my quarantine between the 14th and 20th August 2021.
      3- "Encouragement" card given by the Student Health Centre to help students and staff manage their stress before doing their COVID-19 PCR test. Date: between January and May 2021.
    - Harris, Georgia. Drawing, August, 2021; Submission 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Drawing [submitted by Georgia Harris, daughter of one faculty and one staff member].
      Biographical / Historical
      Georgia is 4.5 years old and drew herself wearing a mask.
    - Sha, Jiara. Daily stickers, January 2021; Submission 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      I'm a visiting student from NYU Shanghai campus and studied here in fall 2021. During my stay here, I collected the daily stickers and stuck them in a pile.
    - Anonymous. Drawings, n.d.; Submission anon (Box 1, Folder 5)
      [anonymous donation of assumed children's drawings]
    - Westermann, Mariët. Library Loaned Items Delivery Brown Bag, July 2021 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      While campus operations continued to remain fully remote during the academic year 2020-2021, the Library circulated loaned materials in a contactless system where materials were paged and patrons could pick them via a marked brown bag on carts outside the Library.
    - Westermann, Mariët. PCR Test Invoice Receipts, October 2020 and April 2021 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Receipts for two separate PCR tests that were conducted in Dubai in preparation for re-entering Abu Dhabi. The invoice shows that each individual rapid test cost 250 AED.
    - Westermann, Mariët. "Below 60 Years" Yas Mall Wristband, Summer 2020 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      In May 2020 the Ministry of Health and the National Emergency Crisis and Disaster Management Authority released a ruling that young children and adults over 60 would not be allowed to enter malls, supermarkets, or shops in the UAE to help limit the spread of Covid-19. Any adult who looked to be over the age of 60 was stopped at the entrance by security guards, ID'd, and upon proof that they were under 60 was given a wristband labeled "Below 60 Years Old" to wear on condition of entering. This wristband was given to Vice Chancellor Westermann's spouse, Charlie Pardoe, during an excursion to Yas Mall, just a few months ahead of his 60th birthday.
    - Westermann, Mariët. Halloween "Masked" Mask, Halloween 2021 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Made for Vice Chancellor Westermann by the child of NYUAD staff member Tina Wadhwa and NYUAD faculty member Kartik Sreenivasan during campus Halloween physically distanced celebrations.
    - Westermann, Mariët. Abu Dhabi Department of Health "Tracker Bag" with sticker, 2020 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Beginning in September 2020, amid an increase of coronavirus cases in the UAE, the Abu Dhabi airport began fitting arrived passengers with a Covid-19 tracking device that they had to wear during a 14-day home quarantine. Although she was not able to save the tracking device, VC Westermann saved the bag and sticker she received the tracker in from the Department of Health.
    - Westermann, Mariët. "I Got Vaccinated" Stickers, ca. January 2021 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      In January 2021, just a month after approving the Sinopharm vaccine, the UAE launched a voluntary vaccine campaign, making the vaccine free and available at all clinics and private health centers. Vice Chancellor Westermann announced on January 19, 2021 that she had decided to get the Sinopharm vaccine as a safety measure, and during the week of January 25-28, 2021, in collaboration with the Abu Dhabi Department of Health, NYUAD sponsored a free COVID-19 Sinopharm vaccination drive on campus from 9am-7pm every day.
      Participants were given an "I Got Vaccinated" sticker upon receiving their first shot. A follow up second vaccination shot was then required three weeks after receiving the first dose.
      An envelope of stickers was specifically set aside for Westermann on behalf of the Office of External Relations. The stickers were designed and printed using the NYUAD Covid brand.
  - Digital Submissions
    - Marcano, Victoria. Distanced [Photos], May 2021; Submission 5 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_005)
      General
      "Distanced" is a series of digital photos submitted by NYUAD student Victoria Marcano, for the NYUAD Covid-19 Archive.
      I am a sophomore student majoring in Psychology and Art History.
      D i s t a n c e d
      The prolonged social distancing measures have transformed people's routines and relationships. Today we are distanced from our loved ones, from normality, from coherence. Depicting activities characteristic of this period of confinement, my work explores how these activities and social relationships have changed, adapting to the current conditions. My images show the passing of time during the long-lasting quarantine, and the human seek for connectedness and companion, now exacerbated by social distancing.
      Most relationships have become long-distance as a consequence of the imposed distancing, and my goal is to represent them as anchors facing uncertainty. This series is a reminder of the social nature of humans and of the importance of relationships as sources of support, because no matter how different our days are or how far apart we are, we are all going through this tough period in our own ways and feel the need for human contact. Distanced is a meditation on how technology shortens distances, allowing for a "company" that is the only source of constancy and normality in a world that changes at the minute.
      In this series I capture scenes of virtual conversations taking place during quarantine, emphasizing on the interlocutor's activities while they make each other "company". Very dissonant activities coexist in one same moment, a video call, reflecting how, despite our different ways to cope with isolation, we hold on to relationships as sources of normality in a convoluted world. I explore the themes of isolation, routine, monotony, and relationships, while attempting to make a universal statement of their importance in this prolonged isolation period. The passing of time is also represented in these portraits through the accumulation of objects in space. This alludes to the duration of the separation and adds to the importance of the virtual company. My images put different lifestyles and activities into conversation, highlighting the sense of irony in how their natures contrast and in where and how they take place. What looks like a fancy dinner consists of canned food, studying happens in bed, one person shaves while the other exercises. Daily routines lost coherence and consistency, but company remains as the motivation to keep moving forward.
      The cropping of the images removes identity from the subjects, bringing focus to the depicted activities and the contrast between them. My intention is for the viewer to picture themselves in the situation, what is more easily achieved when faces and hence identities are excluded. The cropping and the expressionless lips combine to transmit a sense of monotony, routine, and boredom of this long-lasting isolation. Distanced is particularly dear to me as I used my boyfriend and myself as the models, therefore it is truly based on my feelings during this quarantine. I recreated our interactions to represent how the need for human contact defies social distancing. My purpose is to look back at these images one day to remember how my life was like during the pandemic and what was it that kept me afloat.
    - Li, Yihao (Rayna). Studying Away at Home, 2020-2021; Submission 6 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_006)
      I am a member of the class of 2022. I was on a study away in London when the pandemic caused all NYUAD classes to move online. I have been relocated to my home city in Shanghai and taking online classes since, with a pause in between when I did a Go Local semester in Fall 2020.
      1 (photo): NYUAD campus, Jan 21, 2020, my J-term class 'Culture, Context, and Psychology'. The episodic memory about being on campus without masks.
      2 (photo): flight from Abu Dhabi to Shanghai, Jan 24, 2020, the most empty flight I had seen, mostly because people have cancelled travel plans to China amidst the outbreak. I slept very well on these empty seats. The cushion cover says 'Happy New Year' in Chinese. I got a bag of oranges (traditional food for the new year) but I didn't eat them because I did not want to take off my mask. I felt bad for wasting food.
      3 (photo): same as above. An airport staff using a handheld temperature camera to spot people with fevers.
      4 (photo): last glimpse of the sunrise from my London dorm window, the day of departing London, March 12, 2021.
      5 (photo): Ticket to Dear Evan Hansen on March 17. This is a musical that I have always wanted to see, but I had to give the ticket way since I was departing early.
      6 (photo): 7-Hour Layover at Hong Kong International Airport, March 13, 2021. I tried to get some food without taking my mask off for an extended period of time. Photo was taken by my London roommate.
      7 (photo): this is a photo sent by one of my classmates in London, who was also travelling to her home in China. She saw a fully protected individual (likely another Chinese student travelling home after the closure of campuses) at the airport and sent this photo to me.
      8 (text, pasted in the box below): March 13-15. This is a journal I kept during my 'evacuation from London. It details all of the steps I took from leaving Heathrow to landing in China and being moved to a temporary quarantine station.
      After landing, most passengers (including my roommate) was allowed to travel freely to their homes, where they needed to perform 14 days of self-isolation. However, it was detected that I had a mild fever of 37.4 degrees celcius, so I was taken to a temporary quarantine place on an ambulance! This process was so tedious because it involved a lot of waiting in rooms with no AC, blood tests, travel history interviews, and CT scans. Everyone who was in this temporary station was treated as a suspect case unless we were officially cleared after an expert meeting -- the experts/doctors were working 24/7 and in full protective gears! My journal ends with item 18, which says I have been waiting for six hours in a temporary building waiting for my expert meeting results. I had not been eating or drinking or sleeping (I have decided not to do so because taking off my mask would be unwise), and the birds had come out singing. After that, I was cleared and taken to the in-patient department for isolation (for medical purposes), and I finally got to sleep and relax. Naturally, I had forgotten to make further updates to my journey because I knew I had arrived safely.
      9 (video): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FhgpjCazYMs after deciding to do a go-local semester at NYUSH, Shanghai International Channel invited me to participate in a series of mini-documentaries about re-routed international students living under COVID.
      10 (Chinese news article, published on Dec 26, 2020): https://web.shobserver.com/wxShare/html/325881.htm After my go-local semester, I was interviewed by Jiefang Daily on my experience with this programme.
    - Nguyen, Vince. Paper Bag Mask [Photo], April 2020; Submission 7 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_007)
      This nostalgic DIY convenience-store-paper-bag mask was made on April 9 2020, just when people started to wear mask on campus. Notwithstanding the boring surgical masks that everyone else was wearing, I made something that has more of a personality to it. Another mask was worn underneath for safety purposes. I took a stroll across the Dining Hall and needless to say people were delighted.
    - Hernandez, Donabelle. MyNYUAD [Poetry, Photos], March 2020; Submission 8 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_008)
      I have been working at NYUAD since 2014, I started as a Logistics Supervisor and In-charge of the Mailroom and after 2017 I was moved to ERB Lab Operations Dept Headed by Dr. Michael Davis as Research Store Supervisor. I consider myself as o frontliner because even during pandemic we are working daily to accommodate and assist the Researchers. I am happy to work with ERB and will always be grateful and proud to be a part of the NYUAD community.
      This pandemic has taught me to appreciate more every little thing in life, such as simple joys, saying thank you, offering a smile, saying hello or I love you, and a lot more. I realize that tomorrow is really not guaranteed so whatever you can do or accomplish today to inspire or to touch lives even in the smallest way do it now and do not hesitate, coz you don't realize that it touches people's lives one way or another. And I am so so blessed that I am a part of an institution that doesn't just concerned with growth for business but more so, a place and a company where you will always feel safe and accepted because you are "VALUED."
      [poetry and digital photos]
      Capturing NYUAD A Poem about NYUAD A Poem about HOPE, I was able to make it during March of 2020 when we were all in lockdown A Poem about Kindness and living for the moment
      *My Poems are extra special because the background images of each poem are also photos I took...
    - Contreras, Janine. J9 in 2020 [video], 2018-2020; Submission 9 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_009)
      I am a third-year (rising fourth-year) undergraduate student at NYUAD from the Philippines, studying Biology and Anthropology.
      I learned that the human brain is not meant to store information, rather it mainly exists to process the massive volume of stimuli received by our sensory neurons at every moment, keeping only those necessary and consistent with previous knowledge. Hence, over the past few years, I developed the habit of taking photos and videos to help me remember moments I'd like to look back on, along with my feelings at the time.